Remy Paul

M.Sc. B.Ed. Sharjah

Mob: 0525759148, 0501685139 E mail: remypaul2020@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

Seeking a position of Science Teacher in a school that will give me the opportunity to utilize my skill set for the progress of students and the organization.

SUMMERY

Student-focused Science Teacher with more than 6.5 years of experience in developing and implementing a diverse science-based curriculum. Experience in coordinating science exhibition and co career activities like students cultural, sport activities. Acted as a judging panel member for interschool competitions. Faculty in charge for preparing seminars and annual report .An experienced student counselor for the primary section. Interested in implementing modern techniques and tools for the efficient teaching and learning.

WORK EXPERIENCE

03 June 2018 to till date

Institution: Spring Dale Indian School Sharjah, UAE

Position: High School Biology Teacher

04 Jan 2016 To 12 Mar 2017.

Institution: Sree Narayana Vidya Niketan Public School, Kerala, India

Position: General Science Teacher.

April 2004 to August 2009.

Institution: Muslim Upper Primary School, Kerala, India

Position: General science Teacher.

DUTIES AND RESPONSABILITIES

- ♣ Short, medium and long term planning of lessons to meet the state Curriculum requirements.
- Preparing the lesson plans and teaching the students according to them
- ♣ Teaching planned lessons to pupils of differing abilities. Consistently monitoring the achievements of pupils
- ♣ Developing the skills of children by providing them a healthy atmosphere and using the different teaching methods

- ♣ Organizing the groups of children and permitting them to develop their creativity
- 4 Inspiring the students to learn the new things and by doing so shaping their future according to their interest
- **Arranging** meetings with parents and discussing the development of the children.

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATION

4 Qualified Central Teacher Eligibility Test (CTET) from India

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION

COURSE	SUBJECT	UNIVERSITY	CLASS
B.Ed.	Natural science	Mahatma Gandhi University	Distinction
M.Sc.	Biotechnology	Punjab Technical University	1 st
B.Sc.	Botany	Mahatma Gandhi University	1 st

PERSONAL DETAILS

Husband Name Naveen Joseph 30-09-1981 Date of Birth Sex Female Marital Status Languages Known Married

English, Malayalam and Hindi

Nationality Indian P2697018 Passport no

Visa type Residence visa (expired on 27/03/2020)

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the above mentioned information is true and correct to the best my knowledge and belief

Remy Paul Place: Sharjah